<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sidblogs on &gt; sidmulajkar</title>
    <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/tags/sidblogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sidblogs on &gt; sidmulajkar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 16:04:37 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sidmulajkar.com/tags/sidblogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Pi-hole as a recursive DNS server (Explained)</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/setting-up-pihole-as-a-recursive-dns-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 16:04:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/setting-up-pihole-as-a-recursive-dns-server/</guid>
      <description>Got an old Raspberry Pi lying around? Hate seeing ads while browsing the web? Pi-hole is an open source software project that blocks ads for all devices on your home network by routing all advertising servers into nowhere. What&amp;rsquo;s best is it takes just a few minutes to set up.
What is a Pi-hole?    Network-wide ad blocking via your own Linux hardware. The Pi-hole® is a DNS sinkhole that protects your devices from unwanted content, without installing any client-side software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 4 JavaScript Blogs/Resources to Improve Coding Skills</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-javascript-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-javascript-resources/</guid>
      <description>Time, tide and Javascript never stops for anyone!!!
With two decades of improvement, JavaScript has become one of the most popular programming languages of all time. The journey started in 1995 when Brendan Eich created JavaScript in just 10 days. From there, it has seen multiple revisions, drafts, and growth in the form of frameworks, API’s, modules, etc. Today, we will go forward and list the best resources of JavaScript blogs from the net so that you can enjoy the lastest development things in the field of JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Hosting Service Provider 2021 - In-Depth Review</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-hosting-provider-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-hosting-provider-2021/</guid>
      <description>At first glance, A2 Hosting might seem like nothing more than another hosting platform that sings high praises then falls flat on the delivery. The features almost seem too good to be true.
Everyone claims to be faster than the competitors, but twenty times so? Can A2 Hosting live up to its promises? Let’s take a look.
Speed Tests Don’t Lie When this company says it’s 20x faster than its competitors, it’s not just exaggerating to make an eye-catching headline.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
