<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on &gt; sidmulajkar</title>
    <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/</link>
    <description>A software developer/entrepreneur who is passionately curious about technology and shares his valuable insights with the community through his blogs.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 17:26:04 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />


    <item>
      <title>How to Harden Linux(Debian Server) for security and privacy </title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/how-harden-linux-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/how-harden-linux-server/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial help out in how to harden the linux server for better security and privacy.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>How to create a tor based website?</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/darkweb-tor-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/darkweb-tor-website/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, we will learn how to create a tor based website and do we need it? Tor offers anonymous browsing capabilities to people across the world.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>How to Handle the Double booking problem in an app or website just using the database? </title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/how-to-handle-double-booking-problem-using-db/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/how-to-handle-double-booking-problem-using-db/</guid>
      <description>It totally depends, on what use, we are using the concurrency model for using the specific database to avoid this problem.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Databases! How do we know it&#39;s the right one? </title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/databases-how-do-we-know-its-the-right-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/databases-how-do-we-know-its-the-right-one/</guid>
      <description>Choosing the Best Databases! How do you know it’s the right one? There are different types of modern databases available, each with a distinct set of advantages and disadvantages. This article gives you a bird's eye view of the most popular types of modern databases.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Message Queues! What are those and when to use them? </title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/message-queues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/message-queues/</guid>
      <description>Message queues What are those and when to use them? Message queuing makes it possible for applications to communicate asynchronously, by sending messages to each other via a queue.</description>
    </item>

     <item>
      <title>When Indexes are not Useable sometimes!</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/when-indexes-are-not-useable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/when-indexes-are-not-useable/</guid>
      <description>What do I even mean by useless indexes? Indexes that once helped performance now **just bloat your database** and cause extra work for inserts, updates, and deletes. Indexing is a way to optimize the performance of a database by minimizing the number of disk accesses required when a query is processed.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>B/B&#43; Trees How they are helpful in Database?</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/b-bplus-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/b-bplus-trees/</guid>
      <description>B-tree is a special type of self-balancing search tree in which each node can contain more than one key and can have more than two children. It is a generalized form of the binary search tree. It is also known as a height-balanced m-way tree.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Database Sharding Architectures</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/database-sharding-architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/database-sharding-architectures/</guid>
      <description>Once you’ve decided to shard your database, the next thing you need to figure out is how you’ll go about doing so. When running queries or distributing incoming data to sharded tables or databases, it’s crucial that it goes to the correct shard. Otherwise, it could result in lost data or painfully slow queries. In this section, we’ll go over a few common sharding architectures, each of which uses a slightly different process to distribute data across shards.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>What actually is Database Sharding?</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/what-is-database-sharding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/what-is-database-sharding/</guid>
      <description>Sharding is a method for distributing a single dataset across multiple databases, which can then be stored on multiple machines. This allows for larger datasets to be split in smaller chunks and stored in multiple data nodes, increasing the total storage capacity of the system.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>TCP and UDP - Simple yet Confusing🤔</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/tcp-and-udp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/tcp-and-udp/</guid>
      <description>TCP and UDP  A simple open-ended question that can test your whole sort of knowledge. What will be addressed in this post?    - The problem with packets (IP) - TCP pros and cons - TCP communication sample code - UDP pros and cons - UDP communication sample code - Some questions based on them  To start, I was asked a question in an interview</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>What is TCP Slow Start?</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/tcp-slow-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/tcp-slow-start/</guid>
      <description>Does it affect Web Application Performance? Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s a feature, not an issue but can be a problem sometimes while analyzing and designing the app. TCP slow start is an algorithm which balances the speed of a network connection. Slow start gradually increases the amount of data transmitted until it finds the network's maximum carrying capacity.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>How to install Ubuntu using Linux Subsystem WSL-2 on Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/linux-subsytem-in-windows-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/linux-subsytem-in-windows-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>So, Ready to transform your Windows Environment in to your Linux Beast!! Before prcoeeding with the tutorial check if you have the proper version of Windows 10 installed using the winver command in Windows Start options or using the &amp;ldquo;Run&amp;rdquo; command to use the WSL-2.If you don&amp;rsquo;t have the similar version then try the updating the windows to work ahead.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>How to install Flutter in Linux(Debian) based Systems</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/flutter-installation-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/flutter-installation-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>On Linux, you have two ways you can install Flutter. Install Flutter using snapd open your terminal and use this command to install flutter sudo snap install flutter --classic</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Setting up Pi-hole as a recursive DNS server (Explained)</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/setting-up-pihole-as-a-recursive-dns-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 16:04:37 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/setting-up-pihole-as-a-recursive-dns-server/</guid>
      <description>Got an old Raspberry Pi lying around? Hate seeing ads while browsing the web? Pi-hole is an open-source software project that blocks ads for all devices on your home network by routing all advertising servers into nowhere. What’s best is it takes just a few minutes to set up. Network-wide ad blocking via your own Linux hardware. The Pi-hole® is a DNS sinkhole that protects your devices from unwanted content, without installing any client-side software.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Top 4 JavaScript Blogs/Resources to Improve Coding Skills</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-javascript-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-javascript-resources/</guid>
      <description>With two decades of improvement, JavaScript has become one of the most popular programming languages of all time. The journey started in 1995 when Brendan Eich created JavaScript in just 10 days. From there, it has seen multiple revisions, drafts, and growth in the form of frameworks, APIs, modules, etc. Today, we will go forward and list the best resources of JavaScript blogs from the net so that you can enjoy the lastest development things in the field of JavaScript.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Best Hosting Service Provider 2021 - In-Depth Review</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-hosting-provider-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>

      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-hosting-provider-2021/</guid>
      <description>At first glance, A2 Hosting might seem like nothing more than another hosting platform that sings high praises then falls flat on the delivery. The features almost seem too good to be true. Everyone claims to be faster than the competitors, but twenty times so? Can A2 Hosting live up to its promises? Let’s take a look.</description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
