<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on &gt; sidmulajkar</title>
    <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on &gt; sidmulajkar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 17:26:04 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Indexes are not Useable sometimes!</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/when-indexes-are-not-useable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/when-indexes-are-not-useable/</guid>
      <description>What do I even mean by useless indexes?
 To improve the application and the database, indexes need to change over time.
As the structure of the database change, the structure of the tables change, data in the tables change, the application changes, also the queries against the data change.
Indexes that once helped performance now just bloat your database and cause extra work for inserts, updates, and deletes.
wait&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B/B&#43; Trees How they are helpful in Database?</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/b-bplus-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/b-bplus-trees/</guid>
      <description>What are those? Ever used those while searching through the dataset.
How they are useful in databases?
 To understand stuff more clearly let&amp;rsquo;s take a scenario:
Like you have a table, a huge table(millions of rows to go through), and you want to search to a particular numbered row by some id mentioned &amp;ldquo;100035&amp;rdquo; and not only pulling a row but getting most out of the pulled row.
For the longest time, what we do is search the table one by one sequentially (page by page).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Sharding Architectures</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/database-sharding-architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/database-sharding-architectures/</guid>
      <description>Once you’ve decided to shard your database, the next thing you need to figure out is how you’ll go about doing so.Your application suddenly becomes popular. Traffic and data are starting to grow, and your database gets more overloaded every day.
People on the internet tell you to scale your database by sharding, but you don’t know what it means.
 If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the last blog post and want to know more about Database Sharding check the previous blog &amp;gt; What is Database Sharding</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What actually is Database Sharding?</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/what-is-database-sharding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/what-is-database-sharding/</guid>
      <description>Database ShardingHow often do you shard your database?
Do you prematurely shard?
Do you actually need that for your database?🤔
  Your application is growing. It has more active users, more features, and generates more data every day.
Your database is now becoming a bottleneck for the rest of your application. Database sharding could be the solution to your problems.
But Wait&amp;hellip;
Q) What is Database Sharding?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TCP and UDP - Simple yet Confusing🤔</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/tcp-and-udp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/tcp-and-udp/</guid>
      <description>TCP and UDPA simple open-ended question that can test your whole sort of knowledge.
 What will be addressed in this post?- The problem with packets (IP) - TCP pros and cons - TCP communication sample code - UDP pros and cons - UDP communication sample code - Some questions based on them  To start, I was asked a question in an interview,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is TCP Slow Start?</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/tcp-slow-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/tcp-slow-start/</guid>
      <description>Does it affect Web Application Performance?
Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s a feature, not an issue but can be a problem sometimes while analyzing and designing the app.
 TCP slow start is a congestion-avoidance algorithm that balances the speed of a network connection.
A slow start gradually increases the amount of data transmitted until it finds the network’s maximum carrying capacity.
One of the most common ways to optimize the speed of a connection (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install Ubuntu using Linux Subsystem WSL-2 on Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/linux-subsytem-in-windows-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/linux-subsytem-in-windows-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>So, Ready to transform your Windows Environment in to your Linux Beast!!
 Before prcoeeding with the tutorial check if you have the proper version of Windows 10 installed using the winver command in Windows Start options or using the &amp;ldquo;Run&amp;rdquo; command to use the WSL-2.If you don&amp;rsquo;t have the similar version then try the updating the windows to work ahead.1. Once you have the windows proper version then again open the windows start menu and then type &amp;ldquo;Turn on or off Windows Features&amp;rdquo; to open the dialog box as shown below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install Flutter in Linux(Debian) based Systems</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/flutter-installation-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/flutter-installation-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>On Linux, you have two ways you can install Flutter.Install Flutter using snapdopen your terminal and use this command to install flutter
sudo snap install flutter --classic after installing the flutter for the first time type flutter in the terminal as it will install all its dependencies and files
flutter wait for it to install and then move forward to the pre-requisite section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Pi-hole as a recursive DNS server (Explained)</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/setting-up-pihole-as-a-recursive-dns-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 16:04:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/setting-up-pihole-as-a-recursive-dns-server/</guid>
      <description>Got an old Raspberry Pi lying around? Hate seeing ads while browsing the web? Pi-hole is an open-source software project that blocks ads for all devices on your home network by routing all advertising servers into nowhere. What’s best is it takes just a few minutes to set up.
What is a Pi-hole?Network-wide ad blocking via your own Linux hardware. The Pi-hole® is a DNS sinkhole that protects your devices from unwanted content, without installing any client-side software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 4 JavaScript Blogs/Resources to Improve Coding Skills</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-javascript-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-javascript-resources/</guid>
      <description>With two decades of improvement, JavaScript has become one of the most popular programming languages of all time. The journey started in 1995 when Brendan Eich created JavaScript in just 10 days. From there, it has seen multiple revisions, drafts, and growth in the form of frameworks, APIs, modules, etc. Today, we will go forward and list the best resources of JavaScript blogs from the net so that you can enjoy the lastest development things in the field of JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Hosting Service Provider 2021 - In-Depth Review</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-hosting-provider-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/best-hosting-provider-2021/</guid>
      <description>At first glance, A2 Hosting might seem like nothing more than another hosting platform that sings high praises then falls flat on the delivery. The features almost seem too good to be true.
Everyone claims to be faster than the competitors, but twenty times so? Can A2 Hosting live up to its promises? Let’s take a look.
Speed Tests Don’t Lie
When this company says it’s 20x faster than its competitors, it’s not just exaggerating to make an eye-catching headline.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
