<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>privacy on &gt; sidmulajkar</title>
    <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in privacy on &gt; sidmulajkar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 17:26:04 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sidmulajkar.com/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My personal thoughts on Mail Privacy</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/my-thoughts-on-mail-regarding-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/my-thoughts-on-mail-regarding-privacy/</guid>
      <description>Email still remains an Essential Backbone for communication, nearly used by ~(3-4) billion people. I do not use email as a privacy tool for communication. Check the last part** The most private and secure way to communicate online is by using end-to-end encryption. If you send an end-to-end encrypted email, it’s encrypted on your device and isn’t decrypted until it reaches the device of the other person you sent the message to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Definitive Handbook: How to Harden the Linux Server</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/how-harden-linux-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/how-harden-linux-server/</guid>
      <description>Requirements Computer, virtual private server (VPS) or dedicated server running Debian based server instance. Linux or macOS computer for following the steps and hardening the server Guide &amp;ndash;
Step 1. Create the SSH key pair for login (On Computer) Using a root login password to login is good but not great from the security stand.
When asked for file in which to save key, enter serverlog.
When asked for passphrase, use output from openssl rand -base64 24 (and store passphrase in password manager).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: How to Create a Tor Dark Web Site Step-by-Step</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/darkweb-tor-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/darkweb-tor-website/</guid>
      <description>What is a tor website? A top-level Internet domain used by anonymous websites on the Dark Web.
For eg, as we go to any other website such as google.com or youtube.com, DuckDuckGo is an internet search engine such as google that emphasizes protecting searchers&amp;rsquo; privacy,
can also be accessed using duckduckgo.com or also using the tor address of the website
https://3g2upl4pq6kufc4m.onion (using the tor browser)
Why do we need even need it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Pi-hole as a recursive DNS server (Explained)</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/setting-up-pihole-as-a-recursive-dns-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 16:04:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.com/posts/setting-up-pihole-as-a-recursive-dns-server/</guid>
      <description>Got an old Raspberry Pi lying around? Hate seeing ads while browsing the web? Pi-hole is an open-source software project that blocks ads for all devices on your home network by routing all advertising servers into nowhere. What’s best is it takes just a few minutes to set up.
&amp;ndash;
&amp;ndash;
What is a Pi-hole? Network-wide ad blocking via your own Linux hardware. The Pi-hole® is a DNS sinkhole that protects your devices from unwanted content, without installing any client-side software.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
