<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&gt; sidmulajkar</title>
    <link>https://sidmulajkar.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on &gt; sidmulajkar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 17:26:04 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sidmulajkar.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top JavaScript Blogs to Improve Coding Skills</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.github.io/posts/best-javascript-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.github.io/posts/best-javascript-blogs/</guid>
      <description>With two decades of improvement, JavaScript has become one of the most popular programming languages of all time. The journey started in 1995 when Brendan Eich created JavaScript in just 10 days. From there, it has seen multiple revisions, drafts, and growth in the form of frameworks, API’s, modules, etc. Today, we will go forward and list the top JavaScript blogs from the internet so that you can enjoy the lastest development in the field of JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.github.io/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 19:56:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.github.io/experience/</guid>
      <description>Organisation: Tech Sid Solutions
Role: Founder
Date: June 2017 - April 2020
Location: Mumbai, India
Description:  Well, TSS was just a brain child of mine, created with simple notion to help the local aspiring entrepreneur’s/brand make a digital presence of their own with customised tool sets for proper online presence with our guided services and help marking their first footprint. We helped 6 brands through multiple technique by atleast improving the overall flow and business revenue by 24%-32%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 19:09:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Github Link: https://github.com/sidmulajkar
 Sentiment-Predictor-for-Stress-Detection-using-Voice    B.E Project | Datta Meghe College of Engineering | Dec 2019 - May 2020
A Machine Learning Project based on the deep learning model that helps in predicting Emotions which eventually helps in detecting the mental state of the person. Trained the model on the RAVDESS Dataset (24 Actors, 1440 audio files) using the CNN Model with the raw mfcc voice sets. This method helped in improving the overall accuracy from 74% to 93% from the other methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I have no special talents. I am only passionately curious.&amp;rdquo;
Ever since i saw the computer at my friend&amp;rsquo;s house, computers have been my passion. This inspiring zeal carried me through my education at DMCE (not IIT or NIIT😉)&amp;hellip; getting the bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Engineering, learnt new things and started my career freelancing to starting a startup, all with pretty much the same fascination that drove me as kid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Hosting Provider in 2020</title>
      <link>https://sidmulajkar.github.io/posts/best-hosting-provider-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 17:26:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidmulajkar.github.io/posts/best-hosting-provider-2020/</guid>
      <description>At first glance, A2 Hosting might seem like nothing more than another hosting platform that sings high praises then falls flat on the delivery. The features almost seem too good to be true.
Everyone claims to be faster than the competitors, but twenty times so? Can A2 Hosting live up to its promises? Let’s take a look.
Speed Tests Don’t Lie When this company says it’s 20x faster than its competitors, it’s not just exaggerating to make an eye-catching headline.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
